<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>From Ruins</title>
    <description>Masculine self-development</description>
    <link>http://fromruins.com//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://fromruins.com//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 14:14:01 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 14:14:01 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Importance of Morning Rituals</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The number one piece of advice I would give to anyone that is unhappy with their life is simple: go to bed early, wake up early, establish a productive morning ritual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How you start your day determines how the rest of your day will go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you start your day in a low energy fashion – waking up late, putting on a pot of coffee, slowly getting ready, sitting on the couch and scrolling through your phone until the coffee kicks in, then forcing yourself out the door to get to work or school – your entire day will be low energy and you probably won’t get everything done that you wanted to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s all about momentum.&lt;!--excerpt_end--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you start your day like a bat out of hell – waking up early, hitting the gym, pushing your body to its limit, getting ready, reading, writing – the rest of your day will be more productive and you’ll get much more done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Undefeated heavyweight boxer, Ed Latimore, put it simply:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;The formula is simple:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Wake up earlier, get more done.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you cant grasp that much, you dont care about success anyway.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Ed Latimore (@EdLatimore) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EdLatimore/status/662953596301017088&quot;&gt;November 7, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s your current morning routine? Do you sleep in late? Do you dick around on your phone all morning to wake you up? Do you hit the snooze button 10 times before clumsily getting out of bed?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if you did the top 3 things you hate doing (but know you should) first thing in the morning? Going to the gym, going for a run, cleaning your house, doing dishes, doing laundry, finishing homework, writing, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine how great it would feel to have the hardest part of your day over with before 9 AM. Imagine how much stress that would relieve and how much time that would free up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/edlatimore&quot;&gt;Ed&lt;/a&gt; said something along the lines of “exercise first thing in the morning, before your brain knows what it’s doing.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;go-to-bed-early&quot;&gt;Go to Bed Early&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, I get it – you like to stay up and sleep in. You stay up late every night scrolling through your phone, watching Netflix, and making Trump memes. Everybody does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You tell yourself you’re going to start going to bed earlier and waking up at a decent hour so that you can actually accomplish something tomorrow. Yet, there you are every night looking at funny shit on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make some personal rules for yourself and stick to them. For example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No screens after 9 PM.&lt;/strong&gt; The artificial light of your cell phone, laptop, and TV screen &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.popularmechanics.com/technology/gadgets/a9323/the-light-from-your-gadgets-is-disrupting-your-sleep-cycle-15760498/&quot;&gt;alters your body’s internal clock&lt;/a&gt; and delays your natural production of melatonin (sleepy-time chemical.) Turn off your phone and read a book.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Take melatonin an hour before bed.&lt;/strong&gt; Artificial lighting delays your brain’s natural release of melatonin, which makes you sleepy. If you refuse to turn off your phone after 9 PM, you can buy melatonin pills (I take the &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1Qpwukl&quot;&gt;5mg pills&lt;/a&gt;) to help you fall asleep faster. For me, they start working about an hour after ingestion.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cut out caffeine and sugar after 2 PM.&lt;/strong&gt; Studies show that people who drink coffee (or anything else with caffeine) after 2 PM don’t sleep as well as people who do not. The caffeine remains in your system throughout the evening, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.psychologytoday.com/blog/sleep-newzzz/201312/new-details-caffeine-s-sleep-disrupting-effects&quot;&gt;prevents you from entering into deep, restorative sleep&lt;/a&gt;. Ingesting too much sugar too late in the day can cause &lt;a href=&quot;http://lifespa.com/sleep-interrupted-the-blood-sugar-and-sleep-connection/&quot;&gt;insomnia created by increased blood sugar levels&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Drink yourself into a coma.&lt;/strong&gt; I’m just kidding. Please don’t do this. Drinking booze might make you fall asleep quicker, but it &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.webmd.com/sleep-disorders/news/20130118/alcohol-sleep&quot;&gt;reduces the amount of REM (Rapid Eye Movement) sleep&lt;/a&gt; you get – which is the deepest, most restorative part of the sleep cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;wake-up-early&quot;&gt;Wake Up Early&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I would ask my grandpa why he got up at 5 AM every day, he used to tell me, “early to bed, early to rise, makes a man healthy, wealthy, and wise” – and he was all three (for the most part.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s not very many people who wake up before 6 AM that aren’t doing something impressive with their lives. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.inc.com/marla-tabaka/surprising-sleep-habits-of-highly-successful-people.html&quot;&gt;For example&lt;/a&gt;, from our future President:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;According to Donald Trump, you don’t get to be a celebrity, business magnate, real estate tycoon, and presidential candidate without sacrificing some rest. Trump credits his success, in part, to the fact that he gets only three to four hours of sleep each night. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessinsider.com/successful-people-who-barely-sleep-2012-9?op=1&quot;&gt;He’s said&lt;/a&gt;, “How does somebody that’s sleeping 12 and 14 hours a day compete with someone that’s sleeping three or four?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I’m not saying you should only get three or four hours a sleep a night – not everyone is blessed with Trump’s superhuman genetics. Just don’t sleep more than you need to. Everybody’s body is different and requires different amounts of sleep – figure out how many hours is best for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But Drew, waking up early is hard! My bed is so comfortable and I’m lazy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, I know. It’s tough. If it ain’t tough, it ain’t worth doing. If you can’t manage to get yourself out of bed before 7 AM on a daily basis, I doubt you’ll have the self-discipline and willpower to change your life for the better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help you wake up early, here’s a few things I do to help me get up and moving:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Set a sun lamp on a timer, put it next to your bed.&lt;/strong&gt; I have my &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1KZORK1&quot;&gt;sun lamp&lt;/a&gt; on my nightstand attached to a timer that makes it turn on every morning at 6 AM. Sun lamps reproduce the same spectrum of light that the sun produces, which makes your body wake up much quicker and also &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.webmd.com/depression/features/winter-depression-symptoms&quot;&gt;relieves some seasonal forms of depression&lt;/a&gt;. Once you get blasted in the face with (artificial) sunlight, it’s hard to go back to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Set an alarm, place your phone across the room.&lt;/strong&gt; Lots of people like to use their alarm on their phone and place it either in their bed or next to it, which makes it all too tempting and all too easy to hit the snooze button. Hell, my phone has a feature where all I need to do to put the alarm in snooze is to flip the phone over. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cnn.com/2014/02/06/health/upwave-snooze-button/&quot;&gt;Snoozing only makes you more sleepy&lt;/a&gt; – so put your phone on the other side of the room so you’re forced to get out of bed to turn it off.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Try supplements other than coffee.&lt;/strong&gt; Personally, I don’t drink much coffee. It tastes like shit and makes me… well, shit. In the mornings, I mix &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.goodlookingloser.com/entry/kratom-guide/all-about-kratom-1&quot;&gt;kratom&lt;/a&gt; – a legal stimulant in low doses (I’ll do a separate article on it later) – with applesauce, because I’m too big of a pussy to eat it any other way. Kratom is not addictive, has no side effects, and is similar to caffeine – it just boosts your mood a little bit more. With my kratom I’ll have a cup of green tea (&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1KZPBiv&quot;&gt;my favorite&lt;/a&gt;), which has some caffeine and other great effects. Another alternative is to take &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bulletproofexec.com/why-you-are-suffering-from-a-modafinil-deficiency/&quot;&gt;Modafinil&lt;/a&gt; – a “smart drug” originally developed for patients with narcolepsy, allows you to stay awake longer and be more focused. It’s very popular on Wall Street and other high-paced jobs because it is similar to Adderall except without all the nasty side effects. You can get a prescription for Modafinil from your doctor – it is not available for sale over-the-counter in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get your blood flowing.&lt;/strong&gt; After I eat my kratom and drink my tea, I’ll either lift in my home gym in the basement, run with my dog, or hit the heavy bag for 20 minutes. Getting your body moving , blood flowing, and oxygen pumping is one of the best ways to get ready for the day. Your body adapts to needing energy so early in the morning, and after time it will naturally provide you with the energy when you wake up.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember: early to bed, early to rise, makes a man healthy, wealthy, and wise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s your morning routine like? What could you to do to improve it? Do you get everything done during the day that you’d like to? Have any tips to help people get to sleep sooner and wake up earlier?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://fromruins.com//the-importance-of-morning-rituals</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fromruins.com//the-importance-of-morning-rituals</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dear 16-Year-Old Me</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear 16 year old Drew,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am writing to you now, as a 21 year old, to advise you and let you know what to spend your time on, what to not waste your time on, and mistakes that you should avoid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot will change in the next five years, as you are soon to find out. You’ll fall in what you think is love, and get what you think is heartbroken. You’ll make new friends, lose old friends, and then lose your new friends. You’ll move out of your parents’ house at 18 and live on your own, which is more challenging than  you anticipated. You’ll waste a lot of time and a lot of money on things you shouldn’t have spent any time or money on. You’ll learn a lot, lose a lot, and discover a lot about yourself in the next five years that will fly by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with the most important things first, shall we?&lt;!--excerpt_end--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;spend-more-time-with-your-family-especially-your-grandpa&quot;&gt;1. Spend more time with your family, especially your grandpa&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t know how little time left you have with your grandpa, and you will regret not spending as much time that you possibly can. Trust me, I regret it every day of my life. Your grandfather is a wonderful man, and you know that he has been your role model since you were a little tyke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He grew up dirt poor during the Great Depression with seven brothers and sisters, served in the military, started from nothing as a Post Master, became an entrepreneur in the cattle business, and worked his ass off every single day so that your mother, your brothers, and you wouldn’t have to struggle like he did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know you’re preoccupied with 16-year-old things like chasing girls, hanging out with your friends, and spending way too much time in your room playing video games. You have to understand that these are just distractions, and that once somebody is gone, you can’t go back to change things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon enough, you’ll realize that family is the most important thing in life. Surrounding yourself with people that love you and letting them know that you love them is never a waste of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make time for your folks, make memories with your folks, or one day, when they’re gone, you’ll make yourself miserable fretting over what could have been and what you should have done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know you think PaPa is invincible and he’ll be around for a long time, but you’re just naive. Ask him how he’s doing, ask him about his life, find out what motivated him to become the great man he became. Go to Schlepp’s (local family restaurant in my hometown) with him, help him out on the farm, go fishing with him, sit down and shoot the shit – do whatever you can to let him know you appreciate him and everything he has done for you and your family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day you’ll regret not letting your grandpa know just how much you loved him and how much you admired him, you’ll regret sitting in your bedroom playing World of Warcraft for hours on end, you’ll regret wasting so much time on so much that never amounted to anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theworldis.bandcamp.com/track/space-explorations-to-solve-earthly-crises&quot;&gt;Infinity isn’t anything until you are among the stars searching for something you lost.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spend time with the rest of your family, too. In a couple years you’ll be moving away to the (relatively) big city and won’t have nearly as much time as you’d like to spend with your loved ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day, everyone you love will be gone, so take time our of your day and enjoy their presence while you still can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;get-off-the-internet-and-go-to-church&quot;&gt;2. Get off the internet and go to church&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, I know. You’re an edgy 16 year-old atheist and you think you have the whole world figured out just because you have access to Google. If you could put aside your fragile ego and realize that all knowledge is based on blind faith, if you could get off the internet and talk to people in real life, if you could see how extremely blessed you are – you wouldn’t be such a fedora-tipping atheist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I know, you think you’re smarter than everyone else and that’s what you base your entire self-confidence on – but it’s all a sham. Sure, you’re a smart kid, but you fail to see the bigger picture. You fail to see that nothing that happens in this strange, short life is a coincidence. You fail to see that placing your faith only in what you can observe and measure is a fool’s religion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somehow, in our modern world with all of our gadgets, all of our information, and all of our self-alienation… we have forgot how to connect with the eternal. You think you know everything because you have the entirety of human knowledge at the tips of your fingers, but you can’t see anything beyond what’s in front of you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day, you will realize that everything you place your misguided “faith” in – science, statistics, “logic” – roots from your fear of &lt;em&gt;being wrong&lt;/em&gt;. You feel the need to feel &lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt;. You don’t care about being happy, or moral, or just – you just want to be &lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally, it’s easier to feel “right” when you can cite studies, recite arguments, and share statistics to “prove” your understanding of the world. It is much, much harder to defend a belief that is seemingly irrational and idealistic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally, it’s easier to believe in nothing, to believe that we are just clumps of cells that were created by a random accident floating on a rock around the seemingly infinite universe. It’s easier to blur the line between right and wrong, to believe that morality is relative. It’s easier to believe that you’re just an animal who learned to use tools and develop language. It’s easier to believe that life’s purpose is to fulfill every single one of your solipsistic, materialistic ambitions. It’s easier to assume you’re right and that there’s no more intelligent being than Man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s harder to believe in the eternal, to believe that our life has meaning outside of what’s obvious and tangible. It’s harder to know what’s right and what’s wrong, no matter the personal circumstance. It’s harder to believe that human beings are more than mere animals succumbing to our every whim and desire, and that our life has a purpose outside of acquiring more shit and endless cycles of getting dopamine rushes from sex, drugs, and making money. It’s much, much harder to assume that you are not the smartest person in the whole universe and that someone, somewhere knows more than you do and has a plan for each and every one of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I ask of you, get off the internet and go hang out with your grandma in church, read some G.K. Chesterton, some C.S. Lewis – realize that you’re young and arrogant and mistake information for wisdom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Atheism turns out to be too simple. If the whole universe has no meaning, we should never have found out that it has no meaning…
— C.S. Lewis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dont-waste-time-on-girls-that-you-cant-see-yourself-marrying&quot;&gt;3. Don’t waste time on girls that you can’t see yourself marrying&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re an okay-looking kid, you don’t seem to have trouble finding girls who like you. As you grow older, you’ll become even more good-looking (I’m not being cocky, I swear) and it’ll become even easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t waste your time on women just because you think they’re cute or because your friends will think you’re cool if you date her. Looks are important, sure, but what really matters – yes, it’s cliche, I know – is what’s inside.  Yeah, you’ll meet girls who you think you “love” and may even get “heartbroken” a time or two, but you must realize that this was not love, but merely infatuation and teenage hormones obscuring your view of reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can’t see a woman raising your kids, can’t see yourself falling madly in love with her, can’t see yourself growing old and ugly with – don’t waste your time on her. Find a woman who has what really counts: integrity, honesty, faith, family values, warmth, femininity, passion, the ability to make you want to become a better man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Find a good woman that makes you want to be a great man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to be cynical in this world where people only view relationships as an easy way to get laid, as a means to embellish their social standing, as as way to inflate their fragile ego. It’s easy to put up your defenses and keep a healthy distance from anyone you decide to spend your time with, to be objective and rational. But love isn’t objective and rational.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to put your guard down, trust someone, and allow yourself to love them entirely. It’s hard to expose yourself like that, to give someone else the power to completely destroy you.  But, it’s even harder to live a life without love and spend your final moments laying on your death bed, surrounded by all your material possessions, degrees, and memories of one-night stands and meaningless flings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wouldn’t you rather risk hurting your ego by taking a shot at love and a meaningful existence?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d rather die believing in love than live believing in nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though you spent your time on meaningless relationships, you somehow managed to snag a wonderful, amazing girl who makes you want to become a better man. Hell, I wouldn’t be writing this if it wasn’t for her. Maybe these relationships were just a learning experience, and if so, they were worth it. Just don’t spend too much time or too much money or get too invested in these relationships, for they will fade from your memory once you meet the right one (and you will [I did.])&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;stop-playing-video-games&quot;&gt;4. Stop playing video games&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You spend the majority of your free time escaping from the reality you hate, diving into a digital world of monsters and dragons, where you feel like you’re a hero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of distracting yourself with quests, experience points, and leveling up – read books, hit the gym, work on a skill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you spent half as much time as you did sitting in your room killing time as you did working on being a better person, you’ll go further than you could have ever imagined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hell, you wouldn’t believe what you accomplished by half-assing it: climbing waterfalls in Iceland, having your photos of Iceland displayed in the Louvre, shooting behind the scenes at MTV music video shoots, eating foie gras on a mountainside overlooking a French village built into a cliff, becoming a famous Twitter celebrity (I jest.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i0.wp.com/www.fromruins.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/1-23.jpg?w=667&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
Rocamadour, France.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just imagine what you could have accomplished if you spent your time honing your skills, reading books, and networking with people who mattered. You could be shooting for National Geographic right now, being paid to travel the world. Instead, you’ll be sitting in your living room, on your torn up couch (thanks to your future dog), drinking cheap cherry-flavored bourbon and writing this blog post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;stay-the-hell-away-from-the-stock-market&quot;&gt;5. Stay the hell away from the stock market&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day soon, you’ll think you have the whole word figured out – including how the entire world’s financial system works. Guess what? You don’t have a fucking clue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will gamble away your entire life savings, you will sell your Harley, you will sell your camera gear, you will beg for loans from your family that you won’t pay back – all to feed the delusion that you’re a stock market genius and will turn $10,000 into $10,000,000 overnight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You won’t. You won’t make a single dime. You will lose every penny you have ever earned and will be forced to pick up a 9-5 office job just to pay your rent. You will regret being a greedy, arrogant son-of-a-bitch for the foreseeable future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spend your money traveling, meeting people, giving yourself the luxury of not having to work 40 hours a week to pay the bills. Money doesn’t buy happiness, but money buys freedom – including the freedom to be happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The risk is not worth the reward. You were frugal your entire life, why blow it all on some get-rich-on-derivative-trading scheme only to be a complete failure and make yourself miserable?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, you will learn some very important lessons and meet some very influential people along the way, but the aftermath of your impulsive decision making will be your downfall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just listen to your parents. Nothing is as easy as it seems. Being successful requires hard work, not arrogance and greed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;in-conclusion&quot;&gt;In conclusion,&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next five years of your life will be the most influential, most challenging, and loneliest years of your life, no matter what. The transition from childhood bliss and ignorance to the real world is tough for everyone, you’re not an exception. I can only try to steer you in the right direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Focus on what’s important in life, work your skinny ass off, don’t give a damn about what the losers in your hometown think of you, and become the person you won’t regret becoming when you’re older.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sincerely,
21 Year-Old Drew&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://fromruins.com//dear-16-year-old-me</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fromruins.com//dear-16-year-old-me</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Four E&#39;s of Anxiety</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the most prevalent “mental illnesses” with millennials is anxiety., which is not surprising considering our modern culture has destroyed the family and community, alienated everyone behind digital screens, and convinced people that nothing is their fault and anything can be fixed with a pill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a reason the pharmaceutical industry is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/news/business-28212223&quot;&gt;most profitable industry in the world&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;!--excerpt_end--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i0.wp.com/ichef-1.bbci.co.uk/news/624/media/images/78427000/gif/_78427037_pharmaceutical_profits_624.gif?w=1260&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
Pharmaceutical profits&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doctors will peddle anti-anxiety drugs to anyone who asks. They will tell you that you simply have a “chemical imbalance” that some magical pill will instantaneously solve. We live in a very high time preference, instant gratification focused society – people will generally choose to take the quick fix that reduces symptoms instead of putting in the time and energy to get to the root of the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Henry David Thoreau so elegantly put it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;There are a thousand hacking at the branches of evil to one who is striking at the root.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In regards to anxiety, branches are the symptoms: being nervous, agitated, worrying, feeling insecure, jitters, loss of appetite, etc. It’s always easier to take a pill to hack at the branches than to look deeper down and strike the root.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The root is the real cause of the anxiety: bad personal experiences, low self-confidence, feeling alone and alienated, no emotional support system, lack of skill, social isolation, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t to say that &lt;em&gt;everyone&lt;/em&gt; suffering from anxiety has been conned by big pharma or that &lt;em&gt;everyone&lt;/em&gt; that’s taking anxiety medication is weak-minded, just that more often than not, anxiety can be solved or reduced without the use of mind-altering pharmaceuticals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;anxiety-sucks&quot;&gt;Anxiety sucks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trust me, I used to suffer from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I quit jobs because I was too anxious to have to greet customers when they walked in. I stayed home instead of going out with friends because I was too anxious to be around strangers. I would blow off dates because I was too anxious to meet a new person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My doctor put me on all kinds of different medication – Ativan, BuSpar, Effexor, Lexapro, Paxil, Zoloft, Celexa – which either made me feel void of any emotion whatsoever or only made the symptoms worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The worst part about relying on these medications is the very likely chance that you will become psychologically and physiologically dependent on your prescription. If you take them for a long period of time, you could lose your natural ability to cope with anxiety, stress, and depression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These medications directly affect the balance of chemicals in your brain. Over a long enough time period, your brain will stop naturally producing these chemicals. If your brain is “balanced” chemically by an outside, artificial source, it will no longer have the need to produce them itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I told you that you could produce a product with huge profit margins that forces your customers to depend on it for their entire life, wouldn’t you be suspicious or feel immoral for producing such a product? Oh, and I forgot to mention – the government will grant you a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fda.gov/Drugs/DevelopmentApprovalProcess/ucm079031.htm&quot;&gt;20 year patent&lt;/a&gt; to prevent other companies from stealing your product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s no wonder pharmaceutical companies continue to set record profits year after year, even when almost every other industry is struggling (Twitter can’t even turn a profit!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i2.wp.com/usaction.org/wp-content/blogs.dir/4/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/drug-co-earnings1.jpg?w=1260&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not to mention that anti-anxiety and anti-depressants have severe, long-lasting side effects – sexual dysfunction, heart problems, thinned blood, suicidal thoughts, weight loss, weight gain, mania, hostility, aggressiveness, impulsive behavior, headaches, dizziness, nausea, low blood-pressure… &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.helpguide.org/articles/anxiety/anxiety-medication.htm&quot;&gt;the list goes on and on&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-to-naturally-overcome-anxiety&quot;&gt;How to Naturally Overcome Anxiety&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people suffering from anxiety have legitimate chemical imbalances that &lt;em&gt;require&lt;/em&gt; medication – this post is not aimed at you, but trying out some of these methods can’t hurt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anxiety is like the Hydra of Lerna – a multi-headed beast that cannot be slain with a single blow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are &lt;strong&gt;four general “roots” of anxiety&lt;/strong&gt;, and you may suffer from one or a mixture of many – &lt;strong&gt;ego, experience, ethics, and exercise&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ego-Based Anxiety&lt;/strong&gt;: rooted in fear, causes you to question your self-worth, and lowers your self-confidence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your ego is living in the future, worrying about things that may or may not happen. You worry about what will happen if you do this or that, and lose focus on enjoying the present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you care too much about how others view you or their reactions to you, you force your brain into an anxious thought-cycle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Am I attractive enough? Am I too fat? Am I too thin? Is my voice weird? Why did she look at me like that, do I have something in my teeth?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will &lt;strong&gt;never&lt;/strong&gt; be content or anxiety-free if you base your self-worth on the opinions of others. You can’t change what people think of you, but you can change how you react to what they think of you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every person you see will  judge you. Consciously or unconsciously, you judge every person you see. There’s no escaping the judgmental nature of human beings. You can only escape your self-loathing caused by the opinions of others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to get rid of ego-based anxiety, you have to be honest with yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take some time to be introspective and find out the root cause of your anxiety – what is your ego afraid of? What caused this fear? Was it a bad experience in the past? What’s the worst that could happen if you could put aside your fear and live the life you want to live?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Experience-Based Anxiety&lt;/strong&gt;: you lack the confidence in your abilities to perform at a certain task, whether it be social interactions, public speaking, showing your talents to others, performing at your job, whatever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This form of anxiety is much &lt;em&gt;simpler&lt;/em&gt; to fix, but simple doesn’t mean easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s simple: practice doing what you’re afraid of and &lt;em&gt;embrace the anxiety&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I said embrace the anxiety. Use it as a fuel source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stop thinking of those butterflies in your stomach as a &lt;em&gt;warning sign&lt;/em&gt; and start viewing them as a sign from your body that &lt;em&gt;you’re about to grow as an individual&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no change without challenge. Period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can’t get bigger muscles without constantly challenging your body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can’t get better at piano by playing Twinkle Twinkle Little Star over and over again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can’t get better at being social and charismatic by shutting yourself in your room and running away from your problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next time you face a situation that makes you anxious, be prepared for the task at hand and view it as a learning experience rather than a reason to run away and hide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ethics-Based Anxiety&lt;/strong&gt;: when &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fromruins.com/on-moral-ambivalence/&quot;&gt;your actions don’t align with your personal beliefs&lt;/a&gt;, it creates an &lt;em&gt;imbalance&lt;/em&gt; between mind and body which produces anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t believe what you’re doing is right, your body won’t feel right about doing it. That’s where the anxiety comes from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you aren’t doing what you know you should, anxiety is your body’s way of telling you that your inner-being feels guilty about what you’re doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You already know how to fix this one: do what you &lt;em&gt;truly believe&lt;/em&gt; is right and just.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t, you’ll always be a slave to your guilt and emotions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exercise-Based Anxiety&lt;/strong&gt;:  when you don’t exercise enough, eat well, have good posture, or breathe correctly – your body feels weak and threatened which creates anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been proven by multiple studies that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.adaa.org/living-with-anxiety/managing-anxiety/exercise-stress-and-anxiety&quot;&gt;regular exercise reduces anxiety&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a reason why athletes always appear calm, cool, and collected. When you push your body to its absolute extremes, where you feel like you might collapse and die if you do one more rep, run one more yard, hit the heavy bag one more time – your mind and body don’t fear the things that cause anxiety for people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Physical health and emotional health are directly correlated. If you suffer from anxiety and all you do is sit and scroll on your phone all day – get off your lazy ass and hit the gym. You’ll thank me later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Malnutrition can also affect one’s ability to cope with anxiety. Your brain’s neurotransmitters are influenced by what you eat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you eat like shit, you’ll feel like shit. &lt;a href=&quot;http://draxe.com/how-to-fight-depression-and-anxiety-with-nutrition/&quot;&gt;If you eat well, you’ll feel well&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bad posture causes you to subconsciously feel small and defenseless, which causes your body to produce anxiety. Good posture makes you feel strong and powerful, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.healthcentral.com/anxiety/c/4182/152080/posture-anxiety/&quot;&gt;reduces anxiety&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bad posture also influences your ability to breathe deeply and fully. Breathing into your chest isn’t natural -you should be breathing into your belly to get maximum oxygen absorption. The lack of oxygen puts your body in a survival state which produces anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.breathing.com/articles/anxiety.htm&quot;&gt;Correct your breathing, increase your oxygen intake to stop your body from feeling defenseless, reduce your anxiety.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anxiety is your fight or flight reflex kicking in, telling you it’s either time to stand your ground or run and hide. If you decide to fight, sure, you might get hurt – but you might achieve more than you ever thought possible. If you choose flight, you’ll never know what could have been because you avoided conflict instead of facing it head on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clearly this doesn’t mean that you should always stand and fight. If you’re walking down the street and you see a group of drunk dudes looking for a fight, you should probably just turn around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Modern society has created a fluffy, safe environment and people rarely, if ever, face something life threatening. Back in the day, cavemen would get “anxiety” when they saw a sabertooth tiger. British monks would feel “anxious” when they saw a viking raiding party land on the shores of the Isle of Portland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Modern people don’t face these sort of fatal surprises very often, but the fight or flight reflex remains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s up to you, do you want to fight your demons or let them chase you into darkness?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://fromruins.com//the-4-es-of-anxiety-ego-experience-ethics-and-exercise</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fromruins.com//the-4-es-of-anxiety-ego-experience-ethics-and-exercise</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>On Moral Ambivalence</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ambivalence | &lt;em&gt;noun&lt;/em&gt; | am·biv·a·lence | \am-ˈbi-və-lən(t)s\&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:  simultaneous and contradictory attitudes or feelings (as attraction and repulsion) toward an object, person, or action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2a :  continual fluctuation (as between one thing and its opposite)b :  uncertainty as to which approach to follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every single person living on this planet experiences some form of ambivalence between their inner self and their outer world. A disconnect between what they believe and what they do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This disconnect between character and personality – between values and actions – causes myriad of emotional issues within oneself. Knowing deep down that what they are doing is wrong yet continuing to do what they’re doing – whether it be out of peer pressure, out of bad habit, or out of fear of change – causes people to question their very existence.&lt;!--excerpt_end--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why am I doing this?”
“Why can’t I do what I know is right?”
“What should I do with my life?”
“Why am I never happy?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This leads to all sort of problems that are prevalent in the modern world – depression, anxiety, apathy, eating disorders, solipsism, etc. If you currently experience any of these symptoms, you should take a good look at your life and see if there is any disconnect between who you want to be and who you actually are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;first step&lt;/strong&gt; to overcoming your moral ambivalence is to admit that you’re not living the life you know you should be living. You know what’s true and what’s good, but your actions say otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know you shouldn’t eat fast food, but you still get McDonald’s for lunch twice a week. You know you shouldn’t waste time, but you still spend hours a day browsing the internet or watching Netflix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know you should seek meaningful relationships, but you still view women as sexual objects to be exploited. You know you should live a life of virtue, but still fall victim to your bad habits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I have been morally ambivalent in a few areas of my life. Most notably, I eschewed promiscuous behavior and belittled those whom were sexually wanton – all the while I was taking sexual photos of naked and half-naked models and posting it for all the world to see. What I believed directly contradicted what I was doing in life. I would mock people who partook in hookup culture to boost their ego, yet spent a lot of my free time around naked women just to appease my own ego.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/joelle.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Processed with VSCOcam with b1 preset&quot; /&gt;
Joelle – France, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;second step&lt;/strong&gt; is to understand what caused you to perform the actions that contradicted your beliefs. Take some time to contemplate and realize what was fueling your behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why did you eat junk food when you knew it was bad for you? Because it was easy and comfortable, or because you wanted the cheap thrill of a greasy burger and fries?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why did you waste your time on the internet or watching Netflix? Because it was what you were used to, or because you were afraid of actually putting an effort into your life and were terrified of the possibility of failure?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my case, I wanted to exude the aura of “bad-boy photographer who spends his time around beautiful women.” Why? Maybe to get back at the girls in the past who burned me, or to show my bullies from middle school that I’m better than they are. Maybe I just wanted to see if it was possible to lead a happy life by only focusing on the outer world – physical beauty and nothing else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/kelly.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2+(1+of+1)&quot; /&gt;
Kelly – Australia, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though I spent a lot of time around gorgeous women, some of which tried to make advances with me, I never pursued any of them sexually.  I didn’t want to become a “sleazy” photographer that uses his camera to try to sleep with women. I also never believed in having sex outside of a committed relationship (gasp!) and found it easy to turn down models that were only interested in hooking up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know how other men in my situation would have handled themselves, but I am glad that I only gave off the aura of a bad-boy photographer and never actually became a womanizer with a camera. Physical beauty without spiritual or inner beauty is like painting a masterpiece on a napkin – there’s no point of admiring it if it’s painted on garbage. If you can only connect with someone on a physical level, then that will be the extent of your relationship – skin-deep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;final step&lt;/strong&gt; is change your ways and live a life that aligns with your personal beliefs and values.  It is always hard to break habits and start new ones – I never said that this would be easy. I cannot motivate you to live your life a certain way or to be honest with yourself. You only have to realize that any disconnect between your beliefs (soul) and your actions (body) will cause you to feel disconnected from reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever since I was a little kid, I have always wanted to fall in love, get married, and start a family. After a string of bad relationships full of betrayal and lies I found myself perusing “manosphere” websites, such as Return of Kings, that tried to convince me that all women are garbage and the only way to be happy is to have casual sex with strangers that I seduced using systematic, impersonal strategies. I thought that by hanging out with naked girls and making great photographs of them that I would find some sort of meaning in this life, but it was only a distraction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe that many young men find themselves in a similar position that I was in – trying to find answers and rationalization for why their relationships failed. Behind every “pickup artist” is a sad little boy who got his heart broken by a girl he gave his heart to. Instead of accepting that the girl wasn’t right for him and that there was still hope for true love, he decided to spend his time and energy chasing cheap thrills with loose women.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am extremely grateful that I never took the “red pill” and decided to treat relationships and sex as a game to pass the time and boost my fragile ego. I went without sex for nearly two years – with plenty of opportunities – because I didn’t think that any of the available women would make a good mother to my future children. I’ve had girls stop talking to me because I wouldn’t “put out” on the first or second date, invited girls from Tinder to my house just to awkwardly talk to them for an hour before they left unsatisfied and confused, and tried to politely reject girls who I did not feel like I could connect with on a personal level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stuck to my guns and I have been rewarded for it tenfold – I am dating a wonderful woman who I would gladly marry and start a family with. She met all of my expectations and blew them out of the water. Being in love with someone who loves you for who you really are, and not the persona that you show off to the world, is far more rewarding than any hookup or any one-night stand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/rachel-and-i.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rachel and I — Christmas 2015&quot; /&gt;
Rachel and I – Christmas 2015&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deep down I always knew these truths to be self-evident and obvious, but I was living a lifestyle that directly contradicted them. I would spend my free time trolling girls on Tinder or setting up photoshoots with nude models. Now that I have put all of that behind me (good riddance) and have aligned my actions (personality) with my beliefs (character), I feel complete. I no longer feel like something is wrong with myself or this world, or that it’s everybody else’s fault and not my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only you know what’s most important in your life. Only you know what it is you need to do to align your actions with your beliefs. Only you know what’s stopping you from living the life you want to live, deep down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cannot change your habits or tell you what you need to do – I can only offer my experiences and show how it has changed my life for the better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like you to do an experiment with me – for one week, ask yourself “why am I doing this? Does it align with my beliefs? Will this help me reach my goals? If not, what can I do instead that will align with my values and help me life the life I desire to live?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll be amazed at how many detrimental behaviors you can lose and how many good habits you can gain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The fatal metaphor of progress, which means leaving things behind us, has utterly obscured the real idea of growth, which means leaving things inside us.
— G.K. Chesterton&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://fromruins.com//on-moral-ambivalence</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fromruins.com//on-moral-ambivalence</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Three Steps to Becoming a &quot;New Me&quot;</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s a new year, a new blog, and a new reason to procrastinate doing what’s important (like how I put off writing this post for 3 days.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/iceland.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Iceland&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Iceland.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You go to bed at night worrying about what you need to get done the next day and tell yourself “tomorrow will be the day I finally start to get my shit together.” You wake up the next morning and fall back into the same bad habits that have only weighed you down. You know what you want out of life, you know what you need to get it, but you still take the easiest route and do what’s comfortable. It’s not productive, it’s not helping you – but it’s easy… it’s safe. I’m not going to pretend like I don’t have bad habits and procrastinate, I do. I waste time goofing off on the internet, waste time playing video games, waste time drinking, waste time watching Netflix.&lt;!--excerpt_end--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every new year, people seem to believe that somehow they will become a “new me” even though they know it’s a lie they tell themselves to feel better. They will keep doing the same shit and keep getting the same results. They only have vague New Year’s “resolutions” and no step-by-step plan on how to achieve these goals. It’s a sad routine that people find themselves in every year, and I am ashamed to admit that I ain’t any different. Every new year I tell myself I’ll achieve X and Y by Z, but rarely do. I always fall back into my bad habits, my addictive personality, and my stubborn ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I came up with an easy-to-remember method to &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; stick to your goals and actually become a “new me.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;analyze-arrange-act&quot;&gt;Analyze. Arrange. Act.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;analyze--what-happened-why-did-it-happen&quot;&gt;Analyze – What happened? Why did it happen?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take some time to be alone. Get rid of any distractions. Turn off your phone. Grab a notepad and a pen. Lock the door. Sit and think about what you did in 2015 and if it got you any closer to your personal goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What did you do in 2015 that you were proud of? What did you do that you aren’t proud of? Why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What habits helped you? What habits hurt you? What are some bad habits you want to get rid of? Some good ones you want to create?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What did you waste time on? What did you learn? Did you grow, stagnate, or decay?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What challenges did you overcome? What challenges were too much to handle?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you start any new relationships, were they fulfilling? Did you end any old relationships, were they holding you back?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Write down everything you did this past year – the good and the bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;arrange--how-can-i-do-better-when-will-i-do-it&quot;&gt;Arrange – How can I do better? When will I do it?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you take the time to analyze the past year, you have to figure out how to make this year better. Write it down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you did something you were proud of, figure out how to keep doing that. If you did something you weren’t proud of (and I’m sure you did), figure out how to prevent that from happening again this year. Write it down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your habits helped you, figure out what you can do to keep those habits. If your habits hurt you, figure out how you overcome your negative patterns and become a better you. Write it down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you wasted time, figure out why you wasted time – were you bored, were you lazy, were you escaping your problems? Write it down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you overcame difficult challenges, figure out what strengths you have that allowed you to do so. Write it down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you were overcame by difficult challenges, figure out what weaknesses you have that allowed you to do so. Write it down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you started any new relationships that you value, figure out why you appreciate this person in your life. Write it down. Tell them why you appreciate them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you ended any old relationships that were holding you back, figure out why you are better off without them. Write it down. Don’t tell them because they’d probably be upset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Figure out what’s working and stick to it. Figure out what’s not and get rid of it. Write it down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make a schedule. Make daily goals. Make weekly goals. Make monthly goals. Write it down. Stick to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smartphones and the internet give us so many ways to schedule our lives and stay on task – and so many ways to distract us from what’s important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A fun and unique app I use to create and complete goals is an app/website called Habitica. It’s based off of Role-Playing Games where you get experience points (XP) and gold coins for completing quests. Habitica lets you create “quests” for yourself in the form of a to-do list, daily “quests,” and habits. You get experience points and gold for completing quests and sticking to good habits, and lose health and gold when you don’t complete daily quests or continue with your bad habits. When you get enough XP, you level up. If you save up enough gold, you can buy 15 minute breaks, health potions, armor and weapons to protect your character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll admit it – I used to be addicted to World of Warcraft when I was in middle school. If you can get hooked on the dopamine rush of completing digital quests on a computer screen, imagine how good you’ll feel when you complete actual quests in your real life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Write down your &lt;em&gt;specific&lt;/em&gt; goals and &lt;em&gt;specifically&lt;/em&gt; what you will do to achieve them and &lt;em&gt;specifically&lt;/em&gt; when you do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;act--just-do-it&quot;&gt;Act – Just do it.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you make a plan to improve your life and a system to keep track of it, just do it. There’s nothing I can say to you that will suddenly “motivate” you to do what you know you need to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s not enough clever metaphors, song lyrics, or inspirational quotes that will magically make you get off your lazy ass and get to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you think successful people need to motivate themselves to get shit done? Do you think Donald Trump watches TED talks on YouTube every morning? Do you think Putin browses Reddit to find inspirational memes? Of course not – they are internally motivated. They have the drive inside of themselves to get shit done. If you need some sort of external stimulus to motivate you, your success won’t last. It has to come from within.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, 2015 was a great year. I made a lot of mistakes and wasted a lot of time. I burned a lot of bridges and a hole in my pocket. I succumbed to my addictive personality and took unnecessary risks (anybody want to adopt two cats, by the way?) I don’t regret any of my mistakes – they’re learning opportunities.  Despite of all of my failures, 2015 was probably the best year of my (admittedly short) life. I spent a few weeks in France, saw my photo in the Louvre, learned the basics of two languages, read good books, learned a lot about the world, got a good job, kicked bad habits, found God, met a wonderful girl, and fell in love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people reading this article will fall back into their old habits and stay the same person they’ve always been. When ball drops on December 31, 2016 – they’ll be wondering why they are still the 2015 version of themselves. It’s a new year – are you going to take responsibility for your own life and be in control, or be the victim to circumstances?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;so-ask-yourself-do-you-want-to-become-the-best-version-of-yourself-or-continue-being-the-easy-version-of-yourself&quot;&gt;So ask yourself: do you want to become the best version of yourself, or continue being the easy version of yourself?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Hell is meeting the person you could have been.
– Keith Cunningham&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://fromruins.com//three-steps-to-becoming-a-new-me-analyze-arrange-act</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fromruins.com//three-steps-to-becoming-a-new-me-analyze-arrange-act</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
